[
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": " Software is a series of ____________ that tells a computer what tasks to perform and how to perform them ? ",
        "answer": "instruction",
        "options": [
            "instruction",
            "data",
            "information",
            "utility"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "________________programs that control or maintain the operations of the computer and its devices ?",
        "answer": "System Software",
        "options": [
            "Software",
            "Application software",
            "Utility program",
            "System Software"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "Function of system software is to serve as the _________ between the user, the application software, and the computerâ€™s hardware?",
        "answer": "interface",
        "options": [
            "application",
            "program",
            "server",
            "interface"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": " ____________a set of programs containing instructions that work together to coordinate all the activities among computer hardware resources?",
        "answer": "Operating system",
        "options": [
            "Operating system",
            "Utility program",
            "Operating system",
            "Application software"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "_____________is a type of system software allows that allow a user to perform  maintenance-type tasks?",
        "answer": "Utility program",
        "options": [
            "Operating system",
            "Application software",
            "Utility program",
            "System Software"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "There are four(4) types of operating system",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "________ is an embedded operating system resides on a ROM chip on a mobile device or consumer electronic device?",
        "answer": "Mobile OS",
        "options": [
            "Stand-alone OS",
            "Server OS",
            "Mobile OS",
            "Free OS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "Process of restarting a computer or  mobile devices while it remains powered on",
        "answer": "Warm boot",
        "options": [
            "Warm boot",
            "Cold boot"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "The OS provides a platform that enables what to be run?",
        "answer": "Applications",
        "options": [
            "Applications",
            "Cache",
            "Hardware",
            "Processes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "What type of account is created automatically when Windows is installed on a computer?",
        "answer": "Administrator account",
        "options": [
            "Standard user account",
            "Administrator account",
            "System administrator account",
            "Guest account"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": " Which of the following operating systems is free and open-source?",
        "answer": "Linux",
        "options": [
            "Windows",
            "UNIX",
            "Linux",
            "Mac OS X"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "The following is not a function of an operating system:",
        "answer": "Checking for viruses",
        "options": [
            "Directing information from peripheral devices like a mouse or a printer",
            "Checking for viruses",
            "Allowing users to open applications",
            "Allocating the computer's memory between different tasks."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "Icons, menus and windows are part of:",
        "answer": "Graphical user interface",
        "options": [
            "Graphics or games packages",
            "System security",
            "Applications and user files",
            "Graphical user interface"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "The following is not a part of GUI:",
        "answer": "command prompt",
        "options": [
            "scroll bar",
            "command prompt",
            "radio button",
            "text box"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "Only personal computers need operating systems, not mobile phones or robots.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "Operating system is a set of programs that connects and manages software with ________",
        "answer": "Hardware",
        "options": [
            "System",
            "User",
            "Hardware",
            "Application"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": " Which of these devices can have an MULTI-TASKING operating system?",
        "answer": "Laptop",
        "options": [
            "Simple mobile phone",
            "Microwave oven",
            "Playstation 4",
            "Laptop"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "Which of these devices can have an MULTI USER operating system?",
        "answer": "Mainframe",
        "options": [
            "Smartphone",
            "Mainframe",
            "Simple mobile phone",
            "Personal computer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": " Which of these devices can have an REAL TIME operating system?",
        "answer": "Tesla car",
        "options": [
            "Tesla car",
            "Gaming console",
            "Server",
            "ATM"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "Which of these devices can have an BATCH operating system?",
        "answer": "ATM",
        "options": [
            "Gaming console",
            "Server",
            "ATM",
            "Tesla car"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "what are operaing systems?",
        "answer": "Software",
        "options": [
            "Hardware",
            "Software"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "_________ runs external devices",
        "answer": "device drivers",
        "options": [
            "device runners",
            "device drivers",
            "device instructors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "Why is it important to keep the operating system up to date?",
        "answer": "To protect your computer form malware",
        "options": [
            "To protect your computer form malware",
            "To impress your friends",
            "Because it's the law",
            "To avoid buying a new one"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": "Hardware is different from software because....",
        "answer": "you can see hardware",
        "options": [
            "it costs more",
            "a computer doesn't need software to work",
            "hardware needs a person to make it work",
            "you can see hardware"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": " A computer needs both hardware and software to work",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "Smart phones don't need operating systems, only computers do.",
        "answer": "False",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": "One of the capabilities of operating systems: Two or more users have individual accounts that allow them to work with programs and peripheral devices at the same time",
        "answer": "Multi-user",
        "options": [
            "multitasking",
            "multiprocessing ",
            "Multi-user",
            "multithreading"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "A user interface made up of a command prompt is called: ",
        "answer": "Command Line Interface",
        "options": [
            "Command User Interface",
            "Command Line Interface",
            "Graphical User Interface",
            "Super User Interface"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": "When does BIOS run?",
        "answer": "Runs before Windows loads",
        "options": [
            "Runs after you log in",
            "Runs before you shut down",
            "Runs before Windows loads",
            "Runs after Windows loads"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "The operating system is held.....",
        "answer": "in permanent storage and loaded into RAM when the computer is booted up",
        "options": [
            "in permanent storage and loaded into RAM when the computer is booted up",
            "in the boot up program",
            "in the loader program"
        ]
    }
]